SHRUTI THAPA | EDITOR

LinkedIn: shruti-thapa-485116211 Email: shruti-thapa-485116211

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Diligent English graduate with more than 2 years of editing, writing, and fact-checking experience seeking to use my skills in the most productive way. I have experience with articles about fiction, non-fiction, flora, fauna, art, pop culture and IT.

	CORE COMPETENCIES	
✓ Editing	✓ Writing	Research
✓ Proof-Reading	Documentation	Copy Editing
Content Development	Team Management	Fact Checking
	PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	

1) Newzchain, Bengaluru

Executive Editor | 01 September, 2023 - 30 April, 2024

- Theme selection for weekly work assignments
- Edit and publish approximately 6 files daily
- Leadership of a team of 5 interns and led team meetings
- Used AP style, MLA format.

2) Yocket, Mumbai

Document Editor | 04 April, 2022 - 31 August, 2023

- Managing 50+ files and students.
- Working and supervising multiple projects at a time (blogs)
- Assist other department heads and teams with quality, feedback, data, or information concerns.
- Edited in Google docs and experienced with Chicago Manual Style.

3) Kidadl, UK

Editor | October, 2021 - March, 2022

- Running plagiarism checks using Copyscape and Grammarly.
- Checking every fact mentioned in an article, editing, and proofreading for grammar and readability, checking the
 articles against the company's extensive in-house style, and ensuring they are appropriate for the target
 audience.

4) Blacksof, India

Transcriptionist | August, 2021

- Worked on 4-6 files weekly
- Fact-checked the statements and edited the videos accordingly

EDUCATION

2022 - 2024 | Mount Carmel College, Bangalore

Master's in English Literature

2019 - 2022 | Garden City University, Bangalore

Bachelor's in English Literature

EXTRACURRICULAR

- Community Development Project Teaching young minds, 2023
- Fashion Walk, Christ University, 2022
- Volunteered in making and serving food to an old age home, Siliguri, 2023
- Inter house Elocution and Major Production 2011, 2016
- Volunteered in Save the Planet, cleaning the Himalayan Railway Track (Kurseong) and planting saplings. 2016